<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Han Han on Life Deletion Guide</title><link>https://liguobao.github.io/tags/han-han/</link><description>Recent content in Han Han on Life Deletion Guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 12:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://liguobao.github.io/tags/han-han/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tinglin Town "Past Events"</title><link>https://liguobao.github.io/p/tingling-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://liguobao.github.io/p/tingling-world/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://liguobao.github.io/zh/p/tingling-world/logo.png" alt="Featured image of post Tinglin Town "Past Events"" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="part1"&gt;Part1
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Sculpture Garden was planned to become Asia&amp;rsquo;s largest sculpture-themed park, covering hundreds of acres, after arduous construction, it finally became unfinished. The biggest feature of this sculpture garden is that there is not a single sculpture.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My Understanding of Life - Answering Questions from Tinglin Youth&amp;rdquo;
The initial memory about this place only comes from some article by Han Han.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later around 2022, during Shanghai&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;orderly&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;self-quarantine&amp;rdquo;, one of the few areas where you could move freely was in the &amp;ldquo;countryside&amp;rdquo; of Jinshan District 70km from the city center, at that time you could still see reporters interviewing on the news broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, having lived in Shanghai for ten years, I had no concept of Jinshan at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before having a car, places not covered by an hour&amp;rsquo;s subway ride weren&amp;rsquo;t places I wanted to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having a car, places not reachable within an hour&amp;rsquo;s drive need motivation and drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this spring weekend, after watching the cherry blossoms at night,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sleeping well, it seemed like I could go out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I drove an hour to Tinglin Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapeseed flowers there are blooming, I can go see them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://liguobao.github.io/img/post/tingling-world/hua.jpeg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Rapeseed flowers"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting off the highway, I arrived at the rural path,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I roughly understood what kind of place this is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://liguobao.github.io/img/post/tingling-world/wuzi.jpeg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Rural path"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countryside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything grows from the soil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land is a bit damp after the rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://liguobao.github.io/img/post/tingling-world/shu.jpeg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Trees"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small river flows by the village,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broad beans planted in the roadside gaps,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now blooming with black flowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like familiar countryside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like the hometown I came from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part2"&gt;Part2
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After coming out of the countryside, I drove to the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; Tinglin Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking around, it&amp;rsquo;s basically the appearance of an ordinary southern town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably won&amp;rsquo;t associate with &amp;ldquo;Magic City&amp;rdquo; at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opened Dianping, found a mutton restaurant opposite the parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After entering, couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the menu, a bit confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the boss and boss lady were very enthusiastic in receiving, after all, it looked like no one was eating in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sat down listening to the boss recommending ways to eat mutton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half understanding, felt indifferent, just eat a mutton offal hotpot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon the boss lady brought a pot of soup,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutton offal, blood, meat all there, white soup mixed with garlic sprouts tasted quite good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halfway through, the boss lady added a bowl of rice for us, just enough to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://liguobao.github.io/img/post/tingling-world/yingye.jpeg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Restaurant"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went through the long corridor inside the shop to the bathroom, saw there were several private rooms inside,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be used much now, the small shop must have been lively once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just that the signboards are all rusty now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part3"&gt;Part3
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Probably won&amp;rsquo;t go to Tinglin Town again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many places in life, you go once and that&amp;rsquo;s it,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meetings have their time, that&amp;rsquo;s about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people can meet once more times.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>